Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series III. Professional papers
  - Drafts, reprints, articles, clippings by others
    - A Study of the Initial Stages of Spark Discharges in Gases, by Harry J. White [rp], annotations [am], 7/15/1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Variation of Sparking Potential with Intense Ultraviolet Illumination, by Harry J. White [rp], annotations [am], 7/15/1935 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Magnetic Resonance Accelerator, by M. Stanley Livingston [article], 1/1936 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Scattering of High Energy Protons in Hydrogen, by Milton G. White [rp], annotation [am], 2/15/1936 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - On the Apparatus for the Multiple Acceleration of Light Ions to High Speeds, by Ernest O. Lawrence and Donald Cooksey [rp], annotation [am], 12/15/1936 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Construction and Operation of a Cyclotron to Produce One Million Volt Deuterons, by P. Gerald Kruger and G. K. Green [rp], annotation [am], 5/1/1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Cyclotron: A New Research Tool for Physics and Biology, by Dr. Franz N. D. Kurie [rp], 6/1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Maximum Energy Obtainable from the Cyclotron, by H. A. Bethe, M. E. Rose [rp], annotation [am], 12/15/1937 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Design and Operation of a Large Cyclotron, by Malcolm C. Henderson and Milton G. White [rp], annotation [am], 1/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Focusing and Maximum Energy of Ions in the Cyclotron, by M. E. Rose [rp], annotation [am], 3/1/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The System, Water--Boron Oxide, by F. C. Kracek, G. W. Morey, and H. E. Merwin [rp], 1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Specific Ionization and Mass of Cosmic-Ray Particles, by Dale R. Corson and Robert B. Brode [rp], 5/18/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Range and Specific Ionization of Alpha-Particles, by M. G. Holloway and M. Stanley Livingston [rp], annotation [am], 7/1/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Paths of Ions in the Cyclotron, I & II, by L. H. Thomas [2 rp], annotations [am], 10/15/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Present-Day Design and Technique of the Cyclotron, by Franz N. D. Kurie [pi], 11/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - On the Paths of Ions in the Cyclotron, by L. I. Schiff [rp], 12/15/1938 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - A Capillary Ion Source for the Cyclotron, by M. Stanley Livingston, M. G. Holloway, and C. P. Baker [pi], 2/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Recent Developments in Cyclotron Technique, by Dr. W. B. Mann [pi], 4/8/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Analysis of Experiments on the Scattering of Protons by Protons, by C. Breit, H. M. Thaxton, and L. Eisenbud [rp], 6/1/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Scattering of Protons by Protons, by R. G. Herb, D. W. Kerst, D. B. Parkinson, and G. J. Plain [rp], annotation [am], 6/1/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Initial Performance of the 60-Inch Cyclotron of the William H. Crocker Radiation Laboratory, University of California [rp], 7/1/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Specific Ionization of High Speed Particles, by Robert B. Brode [rp], 7-10/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Note on the Scattering of Neutrons by Protons, by C. Kittel and G. Breit [rp], 10/15/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - A Modified Arc Source for the Cyclotron, Edwin McMillan, W. W. Salisbury [rp], 10/15/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Analysis of Proton-Proton Scattering Data, by E. Creutz [rp], annotation [am], 11/1/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Effects of Shape of Potential Energy Wells Detectable by Experiments on Proton-Proton Scattering, by L. E. Hoisington, S. S. Share, and G. Breit [rp], annotation [am], 11/1/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Phase Shift Calculations for Proton-Proton Scattering at High Energies, by H. M. Thaxton, and L. E. Hoisington [rp], annotations [am], 12/15/1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Meeting at UCB [pi], 1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - A Quantitative Determination of the Neutron Moment in Absolute Nuclear Magnetons, by Luis W. Alvarez and F. Bloch [rp], 1/15/1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Note on ?--Wave Anomalies in Proton-Proton Scattering, by G. Breit, C. Kittel, and H. M. Thaxton [rp], 1/15/1940 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mass of the Meson by the Method of Momentum Loss, by John A. Wheeler and Rudolf Ladenburg [rp], annotation [am], 12/1/1941 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Reports of the Academy of Science U.S.S.R. (In Russian) [negative photostat], English translation [am], annotations [am], 1941 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Joule's Only General Exposition of the Principle of Conservation of Energy, by E. C. Watson [pi], [1941] (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Science and Civilization, by Niels Bohr [2 mc], 8/11/1945 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Atomic Bomb and American Security, by Bernard Brodie (booklet) [mc], annotation [am], 11/1/1945 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Atomic Power and Power Politics, Bob Williams [cc], [1945] (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Future of American Science, by Kirtley F. Mather, Harry Grundfest, Melber Phillips (leaflet) [pi], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Drawing Up The Peace, by Bob Stailey (pamphlet) [pi], 1945 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The A-bomb Has A Monstrous Stepchild Called 'Death Dust,' by W. A. Higinbotham [rp], 5/12/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Should the Scientist Take Part in Politics?, by David Hawkins [pi], 6/18/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki (pamphlet) [pi], 6/30/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Your Flesh Should Creep, by Joseph and Stewart Alsop [rp], 7/13/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Experimental Methods of Nuclear Physics, by Ernest O. Lawrence [mc], annotation [am], 8/29/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Need for a Crusade, By Leo Szilard [mc], annotations [am], 12/1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Man vs. Atom -- Year 1, by James H. McGraw, Jr. (leaflet) [pi], 1946 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Civil Liberties in the Atomic Age, by Robert E. Cushman [rp], 1/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The Decision to Use the Atomic Bomb, Henry L. Stimson [rp], 2/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Atoms: Einstein, The Man who started it all (from Einstein: His Life and Times, by Philipp Frank) [rp], 3/10/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - A More Perfect Union, by Joseph T. Votava [rp], 3/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Health and Medical Services in Hiroshima and Nagasaki [rp], 3/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Jubilee of the Electron, by E. C. Watson [pi], 1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Elementary Theory of the Chain-reacting Pile, by Enrico Fermi [pi], annotation [am], 1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - The President's Loyalty Purge, by Robert E. Cushman, Survey Graphic, p. 283 [pi], annotation [am], 5/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Wiser Tolerance, Edmund Ezra Day [pi], 6/16/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Smearing the Scientists: Attempt To Discredit Civilian Atomic-Energy Control, Chet Holifield [pi], 7/22/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - What Science Learned at Bikini: Latest Report on the Results [pi], 8/11/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Atomic Energy Is Your Business, address by David E. Lilienthal (leaflet) [pi], 9/22/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Scattering of Slow Neutrons by Ortho- and Parahydrogen, by R. Sutton, T. Hall, E. E. Anderson, H. S. Bridge, J. W. DeWire, L. S. Lavatelli, E. A. Long, T. Snyder, R. W. Williams [rp], 12/15/1947 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - FAS leaflet [pi], [1947] (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Gamma-Radiation from Excited States of Light Nuclei, W. A. Fowler, C. C. Lauritsen, and T. Lauritsen [rp], annotation [am], 1/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Sabotage of American Science: The Full Meaning of Attacks on Dr. Condon, Chet Holifield [pi], 3/9/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Production of Mesons by the 184-Inch Berkeley Cyclotron, by Eugene Gardner and C. M. G. Lattes [rp], 3/12/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The First Step to World Disarmament, by Cuthbert Daniel and Arthur M. Squires [mc], 3/14/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Freedom Demands Responsibility, by Cuthbert Daniel and Arthur M. Squires [mc], 4/15/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Security by Proscription, The Washington Post [rp], 4/19/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Scientists and the Government -- Dr. Condon Writes to Senator Hickenlooper, Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists [pi], 4/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Radiation from Electrons Accelerated in a Synchrotron [rp], 7/1/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - A Process Aiding the Capture of Electrons Injected Into a Betatron, by D. W. Kerst [rp], 8/15/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Absorption of High Energy Quanta. I., G. D. Adams [rp], 12/1/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Experimental Determination of Rate of Energy Loss for Slow H1, H2, He4, Li6 Nuclei in Au and Al, by Howard A. Wilcox [rp], 12/15/1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Business Week Reports to Executives on Atomic Energy -- 1948 (pamphlet) [pi], 1948 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Twenty-Five Years of American Physics, by Karl K. Darrow [pi], 10/14/1948 [1949] (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - On the Range of the Electrons in Meson Decay, J. Steinberger [rp], 4/15/1949 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Gamma-Ray Measurements with a Magnetic Lens Spectrometer, W. F. Hornyak, T. Lauritsen, and V. K. Rasmussen [rp], 9/15/1949 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Production of Mesons by X-Rays, by Edwin M. McMillan, Jack M. Peterson, and R. Stephen White [rp], annotations [am], 12/2/1949 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Radiation Cataract Survey, National Research Council [pi], 2/10/1949 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Moral Implications of Our Atomic War Policy, New York Herald Tribune [pi], 7/3/1949 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Wind River Odyssey, George I. Bell [rp], 12/1949 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Open Letter to the United Nations, Niels Bohr [pi], 6/9/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Neutron Production by Complete Absorption of High-energy Photons, by Joseph S. Levinger [rp], 5/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The Maximum Range of High Energy Electrons in Aluminum and Copper, Frank L. Hereford and Charles P. Swann [rp], 6/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - What is an elementary particle?, by E. Schrödinger [negative photostat], 7/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The Lateral and Angular Distribution of Cascade Showers, J. Nishimura and K. Kamata [rp], 9-11/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The Scattering of Gamma-Rays by Nucleons, by R. G. Sachs and L. L. Foldy [rp], 12/1/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Atomic Power Comes Out of the Doldrums, R. E. Lapp [pi], 12/26/1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Security, Loyalty and Science, Walter Gellhorn [cc], 1950 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - The Main Philosophical Considerations of Space and Time, by Eugene C. Holmes [pi], [1950?] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Physical Ideas, their Content, Logic, and Social Contexts in the Education of Humanities Majors at Wesleyan University, by Robert S. Cohen [pi], annotations [am], [1950?] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - A Peril, etc., H. Bethe [am], [1950?] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - A Very Proper Gander, James Thurber [cc], [1950?] (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Max Planck, the Man and His Work, by Walter Meissner [pi], 1/26/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Advent of the Quantum Theory, Albert Einstein [pi], 1/26/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Fifty Years of Quantum Theory, A. Sommerfeld (Part A) and F. Bopp (Part B) [pi], 1/26/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Quantum Theory and Chemistry, Linus Pauling [pi], 1/26/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Diffusion of High Energy Gamma-Rays through Matter. I. Fundamental Equations, L. L. Foldy [rp], 2/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Diffusion of High Energy Gamma-Rays through Matter. II. Solution of the Diffusion Equation, L. L. Foldy and R. K. Osborn [rp], 2/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Capture of pi--Mesons in Deuterium, by K. Breuckner, R. Serber, and K. Watson [rp], 2/15/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Gamma-Ray Spectrum Resulting from Capture of Negative pi--Mesons in Hydrogen and Deuterium, by Wolfgang K. H. Panofsky, R. Lee Aamodt, and James Hadley [rp], annotations [am], 2/15/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Cosmic Ray Studies (Cornell) [pi], 4/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - A Summary of Monte Carlo Calculations, by Lemilda Altman [tm], annotations [am], 6/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - The Absolute Energy Loss of 18-Mev Protons in Various Materials, by Donald C. Sachs and J. Reginald Richardson [rp], 8/15/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - New Aspects of the Pseudoscalar Meson Theory, by L. L. Foldy [rp], 10/1/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - gamma-Ray Spectroscope Using a Scintillating Crystal, R. Sternheimer [thc], 10/11/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Interaction of pi--Mesons with Nuclear Matter, K. A. Brueckner, R. Serber, and K. M. Watson [mc], annotations [am], 10/15/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Decay of the pi--Meson, by M. Ruderman [rp], annotations [am], 10/24/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Electromagnetic Cascades in Photographic Emulsions [rp], 11/1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Leonardo da Vinci the Scientist, by Ludwig Heinrich Heydenreich [pi], 1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Report on Present Status of the Study of the Incidence of Leukemia Among Individuals Surviving Exposure to the Atomic Bomb in Hiroshima and Nagasaki, by William N. Valentine, M. D. [positive photostat], 1951 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Notes on the Gammatron, by S. A. Colgate [tm] annotations [am], 1/1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Small Angle Coherent Scattering of Gammas by Bound Electrons, by J. S. Levinger [rp] annotation [am], 8/15/1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Evaluation of Range Straggling for Heavy Particles, by David O. Caldwell [rp], 10/1/1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Range of 18-Mev Protons in Aluminum, by E. L. Hubbard, and K. R. MacKenzie [rp], 1/1/1952 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Interpretation of Isomeric Transitions of Electric Quadrupole Type, by Aage Bohr and Ben R. Mottelson [rp], 1/1/1953 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Electron-Induced Showers in Copper, Asher Kantz and Robert Hofstadter [rp], 2/1/1953 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Energy of Nucleon-Nucleon Collisions, by R. G. Glasser and Marcel Schein [rp], 4/15/1953 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The Social Versus the Physical Effects from Nuclear Bombing, by Fred Charles Iklé [rp], 3/1954 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Bulletin of APS [phc], 1954 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - 100 Top Physicists of Free world Meet at UR to Exchange Clues [pi], 3/1955 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Data on the Atomic Form Factor: Computation and Survey, by Ann T. Nelms and Irwin Oppenheim [rp] annotation [am], 7/1955 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Avant-Projet de Construction du Mesotron, by E. Picard (in French) [mc] annotation [am], 1955 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Fifty Years of Relativity, by Peter G. Bergmann [rp], 3/23/1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Scattering of Gamma Rays by a Static Electric Field, by A. M. Bernstein and A. K. Mann [mc], [1956?] (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - The Soviet 10-Bev Proton Synchrotron, by John Marshall (pamphlet) [pi], 9/1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - On the Feasibility of Coal-driven Power Stations, by Professor O. R. Frisch [phc] annotation [am], 12/1956 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Diary of Russian Trip, by Luis W. Alvarez [cc], 1956 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Coherent Method of Acceleration of Particle Bunches, by V. I. Veksler [mc], 1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Kaskadnbye Krivye Ot Elektronov I Fotonov Dlia Cvintsa, I.P. Ivanenko [rp], 1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "A Visit to the American Physicists," by V. I. Veksler [mc] annotations [am], 5/13/1956 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Mesons and the Structure of Nucleons, by Bernard T. Feld [rp] annotation [am], 4/1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - [Oxford, UK], Clarendon synchrotron, from ONR Tech Report ONRL 33-58 [mc] annotation [am], 5/1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Physics in Poland and Russia, by Donald J. Hughes [pi], 12/1957 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Factors Concerning Education for Science and Engineering, by Frederick Seitz [pi], 7/1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - The Atom, The Oppenheimer Case [pi], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Plasma Radiation in Magnetic Field, by B. A. Trubnikov and V. S. Kudryavtsev [mc], 8/8/1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Coulomb Corrections to Delbrück Scattering, by F. Rohrlich [mc] annotation [am], [1958?] (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Isaac Newton's Papers and Letters on Natural Philosophy and Related Documents, by J. Bernard Cohen (book review) [pi], 12/19/1958 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Proton-Proton Scattering at 19.8 Mev, by Jack W. Burkig, J. Reginald Richardson, and Glen E. Schrank [rp], 1/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Small-Angle Proton-Proton Scattering at 20 Mev, by Herbert N. Royden and Byron T. Wright [rp], 1/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Magnetic Measurements on the Cornell Alternate Gradient Synchrotron, by E. Malamud and A. Silverman [rp], 1/5/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - The Clock Paradox in Relativity Theory, by Alfred Schild [rp], 1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Multiple Meson Production by Photons in Hydrogen, by S. M. Sellen, G. Cocconi, V. T. Cocconi, and E. L. Hart [rp], 3/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Self-Excited 150-Kilovolt Resonant Cavity for Operation at 87 Megacycles, by H. E. Jackson, R. L. Martin, and J. Waggoner [rp], 3/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Handbook of Physics (book review) [pi], 3/7/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - The Great Decision. The secret history of the atomic bomb, by Michael Amrine (book review) [pi], 3/7/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Detection of Coherent Bremsstrahlung from Crystals, by O. R. Frisch and D. N. Olson [phc], 8/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Absorption of 1-Bev Photons, E. Malamud [rp], 8/1/1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Kaskadnaia Teoriia Livnei, S.Z. Belenbkii i I.H. Ibanenko, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Reflections on the Cultivation of Science, by Paul Delahay [pi], [1959] (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Polarization of LAMBDA degrees from Photoproduction in Hydrogen, by B. D. McDaniel, P. Joos, D. McLeod, S. Richert, and D. Zipoy [phc], 1/1/1960 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Cause, Chance and Creation, by Philip Morrison [pi], 4/30/1960 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Elementary Particles of Modern Physics, by R. E. Marshak [pi], 7/29/1960 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - The coherent scattering of gamma--rays by K electrons in heavy atoms/IV. The scattering of 1.28 and 2.56mc2 gamma --rays in mercury, by G. E. Brown and D. F. Mayers [mc] annotation [am], [1960] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Some Design Considerations for Quadrupole Spectrometers, by H. F. Schopper [mc], 3/1961 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - A Radiofrequency System for a 50-Bev Electron Synchrotron, by John R. Rees [mc] annotation [am], 7/6/1961 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Design of Electron-Positron Colliding Beam Rings, by F. Amman and D. Ritson [phc], [1961] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Part I -- Beam Stability Against Interaction-Region Forces in a Proton Storage Ring, E. J. Woods [phc], [1961] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Space-Charge Effects in Electron-Electron and Positron-Electron Colliding or Crossing Beam Rings, F. Amman and D. Ritson [phc], [1961] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Educating Teachers of the Humanities, by Howard Mumford Jones [pi], 2/10/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Observation and the Quantum, by O. R. Frisch [mc], 3/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 'Parity is not conserved' a new twist to Physics?, by O. R. Frisch [phc], [1957 or 1958] (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - A Question of Parity, by Jeremy Bernstein (pp. 65-76 missing) [pi], 5/12/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Wiggleworm Physics, by Jerome Rothstein [pi], 9/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - 60 Years of Quantum Physics, by Edward U. Condon [pi], 10/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - J. G. Thomson [pi], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Fermi Award: AEC Honors Teller for Contributions to Nuclear Science, by Eugene Wigner [pi], 12/7/1962 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Reflections on the Atomic Bomb, by Eugene P. Wigner [pi], 1/18/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - No Fugitive and Cloistered Virtue, by John A. Wheeler [pi], 1/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Genius of the Atom Bomb: Julius Robert Oppenheimer [pi], 4/5/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Early History of Carbon-14, by Martin D. Kamen [pi], 5/10/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Science for the Non-Scientist, by John R. Howe, Jr. [pi], 5/15/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - 1963 Super-High-Energy Summer Study: Part II -- The Truly National Laboratory, L. M. Lederman [phc] annotation [am], 6/25/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Physics Today, (cover only) [pi], 8/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Steady State Beam Loading in a Traveling Wave Acceleration Section, by M. Tigner [mc], 8/5/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Communication and Comprehension of Scientific Knowledge, by Robert Oppenheimer [pi], 11/29/1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Physics Today, calendar page [pi], 2/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Actual Facts of the A-Bomb Disaster, Good Will Ambassadors -- Hiroshima. Nagasaki World Peace Study Museum (pamphlet) [pi] annotation [am], 3/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Criteria for Scientific Choice, by Alvin M. Weinberg [pi], 3/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - By Their Words, Ye shall Know Them, by Glen T. Seaborg [phc], [1964] (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - The Oppenheimer Case: Melodrama, Tragedy, and Irony, by Cushing Strout [rp] annotation [am], Spring 1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - American Physics Comes of Age, by J. H. Van Vleck (missing pp. 27-) [pi], 6/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Two Open Letters/Weisskopf--Weinberg [pi], 6/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Physics Today National Academy of Sciences Awards: Chien Shiung Wu [pi], 6/64 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Showers in Lead Produced by Electrons with Energies from 300 MeV to 1 BeV, by H. Thom [rp], 10/26/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Last Lecture, by E. H. Harbison [pi], 11/3/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Classical Examples of Space Inversion and Time Reversal, by L. I. Schiff [mc] annotations [am], 12/1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Science, cover only [pi], 1/1/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Investigation of Cascade Showers in Lead with X-Ray Films, by Yojiro Murata [rp] annotation [am], 2/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - A Possible Apparatus for Electron Clashing Beam Experiments, M. Tigner [mc] annotations [am], 4/28/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - The Role of Pure Science in European Civilization, by C. F. Powell [pi], 5/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Vietnam Alternatives: A Path to Peace, by David Berkley, David Boesel, Barry M. Casper, Claire Eisenhandler, Eric Eisenhandler, Steve L. Keroes, George Robinson, Daniel H. Watt [mc], 10/7/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Joseph Henry and the Relations Between Teaching and Research, by Charles Weiner [phc] annotations [am], [1965] (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Joseph Charles Henry et la Science des Arts, by J.-F. Revel (in French) [phc], 11/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Photoproduction of Mesons and Hyperons, by R. F. Bacher [pi], 11/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Secondary Particle Beams from High Energy Proton Synchrotrons, by A. Lincoln Read [2 mc] annotations [am], 12/15/1965 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - A Giant Among Atom Smashers, by Walter Sullivan (BNL) [pi], 1/9/1966 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Notes on the Philosophy Behind Scope of 200 Bev Facility in Design Study Report, by D. Keefe [phc] annotations [am], 1/21/1966 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - House boosts NSF in bid for power [phc], 2/1966 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Resource Letter SAP-1 on Subatomic Particles, by Clifford E. Swartz [preprint], 12/12/1966 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - An Open Letter to American Scientists About Vietnam, from French Scientists [mc], 9/1966+ (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Resource Letter CR-I on Cosmic Rays, by J. R. Winckler and D. J. Hofmann [preprint], 1/1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Physicists Praise Oppenheimer As a Theoretician and Teacher [pi], 2/20 1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Oppenheimer, the "Father of the Atomic Bomb,' Was a Bafflingly Complex Man [pi], 2/26/1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Oppie [pi], 3/6/1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Particle Physics: New Talk of East-West Ties, by D. S. G. [pi] annotation [am], 5/26/1967 (Box 5, Folder 35)